insurance companies are starting to use
telematics to track driver's behavior
and award discounts based on how safe a
driver you are in this video we're going
to explore what telematics is and how
it's used by insurance companies keep
watching
welcome back I'm Nicole and the host of
our YouTube channel before I get started
make sure you're subscribed to our
channel so you don't miss out on our
awesome content okay so you may have
heard the term telematics used before
and wondered what it meant telematics is
just the use of technology to collect
data about a vehicle's movements
location and usage this data is then
transmitted to an insurance company so
that they can better assess risk and
offer customized rates telematics based
insurance policies are becoming more
popular as insurance companies are
looking for new ways to price auto
insurance premiums while traditional
factors such as your driving history
vehicle make model and demographics are
still important insurers are
increasingly turning to telematics to
price policies there are a number of
different ways that insurance companies
use telematics data but one of the most
common ways is by providing discounts
for good driving habits so for example
some insurers will give a discount to
drivers who don't speed or break hard
this type of discount is typically
offered through a smartphone app that
monitors driving behavior or by
installing a small device in your
vehicle that transmits your driving data
to the insurance company another way
insurance carriers are using telematics
is to monitor how often and how far
you're driving so for instance if you do
work remotely and you don't do a lot of
driving during high traffic hours you
likely could benefit from using
telematics as most insurance companies
do give discounts for not driving during
rush hour or late at night but if you do
have a commute daily or you drive a lot
at night you may not see a significant
discount on your auto insurance rates
while the majority of telematic programs
can only benefit you there are some
programs out there that can increase
your premiums based on bad driving
Habits Like speeding and hard braking so
if you know your driving habits are less
than ideal telematics may not be the
best option for you telematics is
changing the way that auto insurance
companies do business and by using the
data to price policies and insurers are
able to offer more customized coverage
at rates that are better reflected for
the individual driver's risk this
ultimately leads to better rates for
good drivers and higher premiums for
those who do have a higher risk for
tickets or accidents let us know in the
comments below if you use telematics now
or maybe if you would in the future and
if you have any questions you can click
the link below this video to get in
touch with one of our agents don't
forget to give this video a thumbs up
and we'll see you next time
[Music]
thank you